HIROKO YAMAJI

+81-080-8452-9789 +1-310-878-4588 hiroko@hirokoymj.com

Professional Profile

I am a Front-End Engineer with 15 years of experience in Los Angeles California and currently live in Japan. Specialized in building web applications from scratch using React.js. I am looking for a job opportunity in US to return and live in US again in 2022.

Live Sample

Front-End (React.js): https://www.hirokoymj.com

Back-End: https://hirokoymj-backend.herokuapp.com/
Git Repository: https://github.com/hirokoymj/hiroko-frontend

Technical Skills

Front-End	Back-End	Development Tools	Others	OS
JavaScript	Node.js	Visual Studio Code	Slack	MacOS:
React (3 years)	Apollo Server	Git	Google Meet	Yosemite
React Hooks	MongoDB	Heroku	Microsoft Teams	Big Sur
Redux	MySQL		Figma	
Apollo Client	lodash		Photoshop CC	
TypeScript	DBeaver		Bitbucket	
HTML5/CSS3/SASS	GraphQL Playground		JIRA	
Gulp			Confluence	
Material UI			GitLab	
Bootstrap 3				

Professional Experience

ASURION JAPAN Tokyo, Japan

May 2021 - December 2021

Software Engineer (React.js, TypeScript)

- Fixed defects and added new features in existing React application.
- Worked across different time zone with an offshore team
- Use Git to collaborate other developers. (branch, rebase, squash, pull request)

HYRECAR INC. Los Angeles, CA

January 2019 – December 2020

Software Engineer (React.js, Apollo Client)

- Developed the Owner web application using React and GraphQL.
- Refactoring the Owner web app using React Hooks and Material UI
- Use Git commands in daily coding flow. (merge commit, log)

BEACHBODY.COM Santa Monica, CA

December 2017 - September 2018

Software Engineer (React.js)

- Implemented an interactive image banner sliders using React.js
- Built the responsive landing pages using Bootstrap 3.

STRATEGIC PARTNERS INC. Northridge, CA

December 2016 - June 2017

Software Engineer (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js)

- Converted a non-responsive web site to a responsive web site using bootstrap 3.
- Implemented local weather page using React.is, Google Map API and Weather Map API.

TELEFLORA.COM Los Angeles, CA

October 2009 - October 2016

Front End Web Developer (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap3, Gulp)

- Created responsive landing pages from scratch using Bootstrap 3.
- Built a sweepstakes form using PHP/MySQL.
- Worked with Oklahoma City IT team in different time zone.

JOL MANAGEMENT Los Angeles, CA

December 2007 - May 2009

Software Engineer

- Extended new and existing functions for e-commerce site.
- Migrated IIS web server and SQL Server due to the close of in-house data center.

MC SQUARED Los Angeles, CA

September 2006 – November 2007

Web Developer (PHP/MySQL)

- Built websites from scratch for luxury condominiums.
- Built Contents Management System with PHP/MySQL to generate promotional HTML email.

SONY ELECTRONICS INC. Santa Monica, CA

July 2005 - July 2006

WEB DEVELOPER (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java)

- Built Sony Electronics Design Center website from scratch.
- Setup a blog application in intranet environment.

Education

SANTA MONICA COLLEGE

February 2004 - June 2005

- Certificate of Interactive Media
- Volunteer works in local recreation center
- Maintained a 3.5 average GPA

YAMAWAKI GAKUEN JUNIOR COLLEGE

Associate degree of Food Science

April 1989 – March 1991

Language:

- Japanese (Native)
- English (Business level)
- CBMS (Certification for Bilingual Medical Staff) 300/400 points

November 2021

US Status:

Green card holder